Arnab Dutta

Software Development Engineer

📞 +91-7469953331 | 屋 arnab5021@gmail.com| 🖸 arnabdutta2194| 🗣 Siliguri, WB, India

ABOUT ME

Proactive software developer possessing in-depth knowledge of various programming languages and best practices for development. Solution based collaborator offering 2.7 years of experience creating and applying technology to develop, automate, monitor, and control production and delivery of client requirements.

EXPERIENCE

Quantiphi

December 2021 - Present

Software Development Engineer

Bengaluru, KA, India

- Developed multiple APIs as a part of backend team.
- Implemented logger framework using **Observer design pattern** and implemented reusable APIs for frontend and AWS Lambda functions to log several necessary details to AWS RDS.
- Refactored code for several major APIs which reduced API call time on an average of 300-500 ms.

Capgemini

October 2020 - November 2021

Senior Analyst/Senior Software Engineer

Bengaluru, KA, India

- Built a Demo Portal which is used by majority of Global ADC Management Team to showcase demos to clients, where entire workflow is displayed on portal along with case validations.
- · Generated process models illustrating automation engineering progress, specifications, and details.Introduced methodologies and best practices to optimize and make the code reusable which resulted in reducing development timelines by 30%.
- Efficiently designed and developed many Automation Frameworks like Daily Health Check Anomaly Ticketing, Global Change Notifier System, Email To Ticket Classifier etc.
- Developed reusable modules for End-To-End Service Now automation(API Based Polling) which is now being used by developers from the different team for integrating their frameworks with Service Now and has reduced development effort by 40%.
- Developed cloud-based use cases using Azure and AWS.
- · Built reporting dashboard for clients, from which they can fetch reports of amount of emails processed via Email-To-Ticket Framework based on date filters for auditing.
- Lead a team of two that worked on multiple POCs to establish cloud-based automation using Azure and AWS SDKs.

Capgemini

Analyst/Software Engineer

July 2019 - September 2020

Bengaluru, KA, India

- Designed and developed multiple health check reporting modules for Storage and Networking tools.
- Designed, developed & deployed multiple bots for End-to-End Windows Automation like AD On-boarding Tasks, Distribution List/Conference Room/Shared Mailbox Creation/Access as well as Exchange Administration which are currently deployed in over 20 accounts.
- Developed over 30 Automation Bots using Python, Powershell Scripting languages as well as using orchestrators like HPOO.

SKILLS

Languages: Python, Powershell, Java, JavaScript

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap Frameworks: Django, AJAX, jQuery

Databases: MSSQL, MySQL, MariaDB, Mongo DB, Amazon RDS, Azure CosmosDB

DevOps: Git, GitHub, Docker, Bitbucket, Tortoise SVN, AWS CloudFormation, ARM Template

Cloud: Azure, AWS

Operating System: Microsoft Windows, Linux(RHEL, CentOS, Ubuntu, Fedora)

Tools and IDEs: Visual Studio Code, Powershell ISE, Postman, SoapUI, Service Now, BMC Remedy, HPOO

EDUCATION

Dr. Bidhan Chandra Roy Engineering College

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communications Engineering. 8.56 CGPA

Aug. 2015 – June 2019 Durgapur, WB, India

CERTIFICATIONS

Coursera: Python For Everybody (04/2020 - Present)

IIEC DOT: Docker (05/2020 - Present)

Coursera : Agile Software Development (03/2021 - Present)

Microsoft : Azure Fundamentals - AZ-900 (06/2021 - 06/2023)

Coursera: Git & Github (06/2021 - Present)

Microsoft: Azure Administrator Associate - AZ-104 (08/2021 - 08/2022)

Coursera: Django For Everybody (11/2021-Present)

ACHIEVEMENTS

1st Rank - Capgemini L1 Training Schedule.

2nd Rank - Capgemini Simulation Lab - Problem Solving (Python & Unix).

Stand Out Performer Q3 - Best Performer of Q3 2020 - Capgemini.

Propeller H1 - Best Performer of H1 2021 - Capgemini.

Other Recognition - Received appreciation from GCC Leadership and project's EVP(Executive Vice President) for developing and deploying multiple Automation Frameworks.

Trainer and Assessor - Trained and assessed multiple fresher batches on technologies like Windows, Linux and Database.

Interests - Event Management, Football, Table Tennis.